

ABDELFATTAH RAGAB

FRONTEND ANGULAR DEVELOPER - ANGULAR / REACT / VUE

P: +20 101 520 0146

E: mscaragab@gmail.com

W: linkedin.com/in/mscaragab

STATEMENT

Professional Frontend Angular Developer with 5+ years of experience. I have handson Angular, PWAs, SPAs, Offline, Background Sync, Push Notifications, Native Features (Camera, GeoLocation...), React, and Vue. With strong knowledge of Object Oriented JavaScript programming and comprehensive experience in backend development. I'm also certified AWS

FRONTEND SKILLS

Angular
PWAs
SPAs
Offline
Background Sync
Push Notifications
Native Features (Camera, Geolocation...)
Material Design
JavaScript
TypeScript
NgRx/RxJS
Git

MOBILE SKILLS

Ionic React Native Flutter Android Kotlin iOS Swift

LANGUAGES

Arabic \star \star \star \star \star English \star \star \star \star German \star \star \star \star Spanish \star \star \star \star

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science

Cairo University, Egypt
Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence

Bachelor of Computer Science

Cairo University, Egypt Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence

EXPERIENCE

Freelance, Egypt

Frontend Angular Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

In Progress

2008

02 Years

Key Job Responsibilities & Achievements

- PWAs and SPAs using Angular, Angular Material, NgRx, RxJS, Service Worker, and Native Device Features.
- Mobile first responsive designs.
- Handling various projects on different stages of development.
- Translating UI/UX design wireframes to actual code.
- Validating the input before submitting it to the back end.
- Using Material Design, Flex Layout, Sass, CSS Flex, and CSS grid.
- Consuming REST APIs, NodeJS, JAVA, NET, PHP, and....
- Using Google Cloud Functions.
- Using AWS Lambda.
- Using Netlify Functions.
- Used Firebase databas, hosting, and authentication.
- Used netlify hosting
- Used AWS S3 hosting.
- Good experience in backend technologies like Java, PHP, .NET, and NodeJS.
- Good experience in Agile methodologies like Scrum.
- Good experience in Software Architecture.
- Work samples and source code are available at my github.
- ** Learn continously and always up to date. **

siParadigm Diagnostic Informatics, Egypt

02 Years

Senior Software Engineer

May 2017 - Jan 2019

Key Job Responsibilities & Achievements

- Attend scrum meetings and use Jira for Agile software development.
- Produce quality coding of features and fixes for the platform.
- Apply DevOps practices and setup the CI/CD pipeline.
- Optimize the complex SQL queries.
- Develop the back end system using Java, Java EE, JSP, Hibernate, MySQL.
- Use advanced JavaScript techniques to invent the Primefaces Genes control.
- Grow engineering teams by interviewing, recruiting and hiring.
- Generate PDF reports using Jasper Reports.
- Generate Word reports using the Apache POI Word Document library.

COURSES

Udemy - Angular - The Complete Guide (2020 Edition)

Develop applications with Angular 10.

Udemy - Angular (Full App) with Angular Material, Angularfire & NgRx

Use Angular, Angular Material, Angularfire (+ Firebase with Firestore) and NgRx to build a real Angular App.

Udemy - Progressive Web Apps (PWA) - The Complete Guide

Build a Progressive Web App (PWA) that feels like an iOS & Android App, using Device Camera, Push Notifications and more

Udemy - NodeJS - The Complete Guide (incl. MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL)

Master Node JS & Deno.js, build REST APIs with Node.js, GraphQL APIs, Authentication, use MongoDB, SQL & much more!

Udemy - CSS - The Complete Guide 2020 (incl. Flexbox, Grid & Sass)

Learn CSS to advanced level.

BACKEND SKILLS

Node.js

C#

.NET PHP

Laravel

Java Kafka

Spring Boot

Microservices

Kubernetes

AWS

Google Cloud

PORTFOLIO

Github

http://github.com/mscaragab

Portfolio

http://mscaragab.github.ic

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Freelance, Egypt

03 Years

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2014 - May 2017

Key Job Responsibilities & Achievements

- Developed a School Management System allowing schools to digitally monitor the daily activities along with managing all the resources and information on a single platform.
- Developed a network marketing, and referral marketing website.
- Beside my working as a freelance developer, I experienced copy-writing, social media
 marketing, authoring books, writing articles, publishing advertisements, optimizing
 search engines, and setting up an online store for WordPress, Drupal, Facebook and
 much More!

Microtech Software Solutions, Egypt

02 Years

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2012 - Apr 2014

Key Job Responsibilities & Achievements

- Develop the Infinity ERP system using C#, JavaScript, and ASP.NET.
- Develop the system portal using ExtJs and JavaScript.
- Develop the spreadsheet modules of the system using Spread.Net and jQuery.
- Use DevExpress controls and themes.
- Develop intuitive software that exceeded the needs of the company.
- Develop system and training documentation as needed.
- Fix the issues reported by application users.
- Recommend improvements to existing features as necessary.
- Design, develop and implement full stack solutions.

Arabia IT Company, Egypt

04 Years

Software Engineer

May 2008 - Apr 2012

Key Job Responsibilities & Achievements

- Develop desktop and web applications using C#, JavaScript and ASP.NET.
- Contribute in all phases of the development lifecycle.
- Develop features across multiple applications.
- Write well designed, testable, efficient code.
- Clearly communicate technical concepts.
- Ensure designs are in compliance with specifications.
- Develop plugins for Adobe products using C++.
- Develop rich client features using jquery and jqueryui.

CERTIFICATES



Google Cloud

Certified Professional Cloud Architect

Jan 2021



Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Jan 2020



racle

Apr 2019

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer